A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, John E. Harr papers FA1219
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, John E. Harr
1959-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
Harr, John Ensor (1926-)
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978
FA1219
15.18 Cubic Feet 35 letter-sized document boxes; 4 legal-sized document boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents Note
These records document John E. Harr's tenure as associate to John D. Rockefeller 3rd, from 1967 to 1978. He worked on writing and research projects for Mr. Rockefeller, such as planning for his book on the future of philanthropy/the third sector in the United States.
In particular, Dr. Harr served as a proxy for Mr. Rockefeller on the National Committee for the Bicentennial Era in the years leading up to the 1976 Bicentennial celebration. The committee's extensive efforts are documented throughout this collection. Others topics of note are Mr. Rockefeller's activities regarding population growth, abortion, euthanasia, youth wellbeing, and public service. Lastly, this collection contains background material about Mr. Rockefeller's interests and activities in Asia that was aggregated by Dr. Harr and his co-author, Peter Johnson, for their two books on the Rockefeller family.
Arrangement
Arranged as received.
Biographical/Historical Note
John Ensor Harr worked as an associate of John D. Rockefeller 3rd from 1967 to 1978, focusing on research, writing, and public relations activities. He later served as vice president of Capital Cities/ABC Inc. as the project director of Project Literacy U.S. (PLUS). Dr. Harr held a doctorate in political science from the University of California, Berkeley, and was the author of several books on foreign affairs. Along with Peter Johnson, Dr. Harr co-authored two books on the Rockefeller family: "The Rockefeller Century" in 1988 and "The Rockefeller Conscience" in 1991. Born in 1926, John Harr attended Beloit College in Wisconsin, where he later served on the board of trustees. He died November 14, 2004.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Harr files were transferred to RAC over the course of several years in the early to mid-1980s, including but not limited to accessions 1982:013 and 1985:172.
- Memos from John E. Harr to John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd Introduction: Asian Cultural Program, 1977 December (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Third Hoover Commission (National Government), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "The Bicentennial: A Missed Opportunity?" Three articles by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- General Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Book on Third Sector, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Book on Third Sector, Preface, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Reader's Digest Article on Third Sector, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Across the Board Article on Third Sector, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Princeton Interview, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bicentennial Second Revolution Articles, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Reader's Digest Article, 1975 February (Box 2, Folder 15)
- New York Times Op-Ed Piece, 1975 February (Box 2, Folder 16)
- U.S. News and World Report Bicentennial Statement, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Bicentennial News Bureau, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- U.S. News and World Report Article: Philanthropy and Taxes, 1974 April (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Family Health Magazine Article, 1974 December (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Newsweek Article: "My Turn" on Bicentennial, 1974 April (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Statements on Inauguration of Jay Rockefeller as Governor of West Virginia, 1977 January (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Press Foundation of Asia, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Alex Haley Roots Foundation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards Selection Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards Selection Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Council for National Policy Planning, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Beloit College Correspondence and Board of Trustees, 1967-1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Rockefeller Archive Center Proposed Fellows Program, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- General Speech Material, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- U.S.–Japan Relations Speech Material, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Background Material for Speeches, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- West Virginia Speech, 1973 September 28 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Minneapolis, MN, Third Sector Speech, 1977 June 30 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Various Speech Opportunities, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Congressional Breakfast Remarks, 1977 August 19 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Duke University Remarks, 1977 October 19 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Select Committee on Population Testimony, 1978 February 9 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Japan House Visit by Prince and Princess Hitachi, 1978 April 8 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Newsweek Article: "My Turn" on Abortion, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Society for the Right to Die, 1970-1978 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Euthanasia White Paper, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Suicide/Euthanasia, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- National Endowment for the Bicentennial Era, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Bicentennial Commission on American Government, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Bicentennial Events and Outcomes, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- National Endowment for the Humanities, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Population Council: Annual Report Introduction, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Third Sector Drafts, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Congressional Seminar on Third Sector, 1976 December (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Third Sector Drafts, 1977 April (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Third Sector Correspondence, 1977 April-May (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Thoughts for a Book on Philanthropy, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Population and Fertility, 1967-1978 (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 63)
- Education Policy Center, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 64)
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd Biographical Material, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 65)
- Foreword to Book by Prakash Sethi, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 66)
- "Of Anniversaries and Revolutions" Article, 1973 May (Box 7, Folder 67)
- "Second American Revolution" Book, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 68)
- Chronological File, 1967 August-December (Box 7, Folder 69)
- Chronological File, 1968 January-June (Box 7, Folder 70)
- Chronological File, 1968 July-December (Box 7, Folder 71)
- Chronological File, 1969 January-June (Box 7, Folder 72)
- Chronological File, 1969 July-December (Box 7, Folder 73)
- Chronological File, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 74)
- Chronological File, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 75)
- Chronological File, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 76)
- Chronological File, 1973 January-June (Box 8, Folder 77)
- Chronological File, 1973 July-December (Box 8, Folder 78)
- General Correspondence, 1973 January-February (Box 8, Folder 79)
- General Correspondence, 1973 March-November (Box 8, Folder 80)
- Miscellaneous Funding Requests, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 81)
- Personal Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 82)
- Personal Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 83)
- Jimmy Carter Speech Draft, 1976 September (Box 9, Folder 84)
- Agricultural Development Council, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 85)
- Caribbean Council, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 86)
- Francis Offner, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 87)
- Miscellaneous unfoldered materials, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 88)
- New Federalist Papers, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 89)
- New Federalist Papers, 1972-1975 (Box 9, Folder 90)
- Bicentennial Declaration of Principles and Purposes, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 91)
- Bicentennial Declaration Drafts, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 92)
- Bicentennial Project Summaries, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 93)
- Liberty Park, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 94)
- Bicentennial Research Project: Yankelovich, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 95)
- Bicentennial Ethnic/Racial Council, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 96)
- Acquisition of USA-200, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 97)
- USA-200, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 98)
- Bicentennial Publications, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 99)
- USA-200 Prospectus, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 100)
- Prospectus Drafts, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 101)
- Prospectus Drafts, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 102)
- Distribution of "Second American Revolution", 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 103)
- Preface for Spanish Edition of "Second American Revolution", 1975 (Box 11, Folder 104)
- "Second American Revolution" Follow-up, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 105)
- Speech Materials, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 106)
- American Issues Forum, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 107)
- American Issues Forum National Planning Group, 1974 May (Box 11, Folder 108)
- American Issues Forum Report, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 109)
- Citizens Involvement Network, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 110)
- Citizens Involvement Network, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 111)
- Citizens Involvement Network, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 112)
- Citizens Involvement Network, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 113)
- Citizens Involvement Network, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 114)
- Citizens Involvement Network, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 115)
- Staff Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 116)
- Bicentennial Task Force Meeting, 1975 October (Box 12, Folder 117)
- Bicentennial Task Force Meeting, 1974 June (Box 12, Folder 118)
- American Revolution Bicentennial Administration, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 119)
- Bicentennial Role of Vice President Nelson Rockefeller, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 120)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 121)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 122)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era Board Letter, 1976 July (Box 13, Folder 123)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 124)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 125)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era Meeting Information, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 126)
- National Academy of Public Administration, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 127)
- National Academy of Public Administration, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 128)
- Jonas Salk's Bicentennial Project, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 129)
- Corporate Bicentennial Projects, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 130)
- Corporate Bicentennial Projects, 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 131)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 132)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 133)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 134)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 135)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 136)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 137)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 138)
- Unsorted Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 15, Folder 139)
- Bicentennial Books Project, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 140)
- A Proposal for the Bicentennial Year, 1975 December (Box 15, Folder 141)
- Third Sector Book Correspondence, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 142)
- Private Sector Bicentennial Plan, 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 143)
- Private Sector Bicentennial Plan, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 144)
- Private Sector Bicentennial Plan, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 145)
- Private Sector Signatories File, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 146)
- Bicentennial Books Project, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 147)
- Institute for the Study of Civic Values, 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 148)
- Bicentennial General Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 16, Folder 149)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 150)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1974-1975 (Box 17, Folder 151)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 152)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1973-1975 (Box 17, Folder 153)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1974 January (Box 17, Folder 154)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1974-1975 (Box 17, Folder 155)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 156)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1975-1979 (Box 18, Folder 157)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 158)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 159)
- National Committee for Bicentennial Era: Unsorted, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 160)
- Communications Program of the Bicentennial Committee, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 161)
- Afro-American Bicentennial Corporation, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 162)
- American Indian Bicentennial Corporation, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 163)
- General Bicentennial Correspondence, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 164)
- General Bicentennial Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 165)
- General Bicentennial Correspondence, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 166)
- General Bicentennial Correspondence, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 167)
- Bicentennial Speaking Points, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 168)
- Bicentennial Meeting, 1974 April 15 (Box 19, Folder 169)
- Bicentennial Closing Letter: JDR 3rd Fund, 1974 April (Box 19, Folder 170)
- Bicentennial Meeting, 1974 April (Box 19, Folder 171)
- Committee for the Future Inc., 1973 (Box 19, Folder 172)
- Bicentennial Meeting, 1973 June (Box 19, Folder 173)
- Open Channel Corporation, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 174)
- Private Sector Discussions, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 175)
- Lincoln Center Bicentennial Plans, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 176)
- Harr's List of the Best Bicentennial Projects, 1974 July (Box 19, Folder 177)
- Bicentennial Plans of Goals for Dallas, 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 178)
- Bicentennial Private Sector Initiative, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 179)
- Bicentennial Private Sector Initiative, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 180)
- Federalism 76 Project, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 181)
- Federalism 76 Project, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 182)
- National Academy of Public Administration: Book Material, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 183)
- National Academy of Public Administration: Book Material, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 184)
- Cambridge Institute Bicentennial Project, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 185)
- Heritage '76, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 186)
- Youth Conference on the Bicentennial, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 187)
- JDR 3rd's Bicentennial Involvement, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 188)
- JDR 3rd's Bicentennial Involvement, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 189)
- Nelson Rockefeller and Third Century, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 190)
- Horizons '76: Call for Achievement, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 191)
- Horizons '76: Call for Achievement, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 192)
- World Population Packet, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 193)
- World Leaders Statement, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 194)
- "Family Weekly" Article Planning, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 195)
- Bicentennial Article Comments, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 196)
- Unsolicited Bicentennial Projects Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 197)
- Unsolicited Bicentennial Projects Correspondence, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 198)
- Unsolicited Bicentennial Projects Correspondence, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 199)
- Unsolicited Bicentennial Projects Correspondence, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 200)
- Bicentennial Job Applicants, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 201)
- Second American Revolution Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 202)
- Second American Revolution Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 203)
- Japan and Korea Trip, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 204)
- USA-200 Correspondence: Volume 1, 1972-1973 (Box 23, Folder 205)
- USA-200 Correspondence: Volume 2, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 206)
- USA-200 Correspondence: Volume 3, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 207)
- Report on Bicentennial State Commissions: Alabama-Hawaii, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 208)
- Report on Bicentennial State Commissions: Idaho-North Dakota, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 209)
- Report on Bicentennial State Commissions: Ohio-Wyoming, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 210)
- Bicentennial Ethnic/Racial Coalition, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 211)
- Bicentennial Planning Meeting, 1975 January 3 (Box 23, Folder 212)
- American Issues Forum: Bicentennial Efforts, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 213)
- International Exposition Inc.: Bicentennial Planning, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 214)
- Reader's Digest Article on Third Sector, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 215)
- Reader's Digest Article on Third Sector: Drafts, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 216)
- Third Sector Drafts, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 217)
- Third Sector Drafts and Notes, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 218)
- Third Sector Drafts and Notes, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 219)
- Duke University Conference on Corporate Social Responsibility, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 220)
- Duke University Conference on Corporate Social Responsibility, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 221)
- Corporate Responsibility, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 222)
- Corporate Responsibility Readings, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 223)
- Corporate Responsibility Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 224)
- Financing Community Report, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 225)
- Human Settlements Information, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 226)
- Bicentennial Readings, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 227)
- Bicentennial Readings, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 228)
- Bicentennial Readings, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 229)
- Bicentennial Readings, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 230)
- John Harr's Writings, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 231)
- Citizens Conference on State Legislatures, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 232)
- Public Appearance Declinations, 1968-1971 (Box 26, Folder 233)
- Articles and Books on John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1968-1971 (Box 26, Folder 234)
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd Appearances on Film, Radio, and TV, 1965-1971 (Box 26, Folder 235)
- Development Assistance, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 236)
- Lincoln Center Printed Materials, 1967-1970 (Box 26, Folder 237)
- Public Broadcasting/Channel 13, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 238)
- Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1968-1970 (Box 26, Folder 239)
- Minority Education, 1967-1970 (Box 26, Folder 240)
- Government and Philanthropy, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 241)
- Commission on Foundations and Private Philanthropy, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 242)
- Corporate Philanthropy, 1961-1970 (Box 26, Folder 243)
- Philanthropy Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 244)
- Philanthropy, General, 1964-1970 (Box 27, Folder 245)
- Technical Assistance Articles, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 246)
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1968-1971 (Box 27, Folder 247)
- American Foreign Service Association, 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 248)
- Asia, 1967-1970 (Box 27, Folder 249)
- Corporate Philanthropy, 1974-1978 (Box 27, Folder 250)
- Staff Retreat, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 251)
- Lunch Meetings, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 252)
- Operation Involvement: Television Program Proposal, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 253)
- Fund for Investigative Journalism, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 254)
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd Articles and Remarks, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 255)
- Boys' Club of New York, 1968-1971 (Box 28, Folder 256)
- Youth Task Force, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 257)
- Youth Task Force, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 258)
- Journal of Applied Behavioral Sciences, 1968-1971 (Box 28, Folder 259)
- Letters of Application, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 260)
- Interviewed Applicants, 1968-1971 (Box 28, Folder 261)
- Citizen Involvement Network, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 262)
- National Academy of Public Administration, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 263)
- National Academy of Public Administration, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 264)
- Right to Die, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 265)
- Population Growth Testimony, 1978 February (Box 29, Folder 266)
- Population Growth Testimony, 1978 January-1978 February (Box 29, Folder 267)
- Euthanasia, 1976-1978 (Box 29, Folder 268)
- Euthanasia Educational Council, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 269)
- National Endowment for the Humanities Challenge Grants, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 270)
- Japan Society, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 271)
- Column on Abortion, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 272)
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd's Ongoing Commitments, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 273)
- Third-Century Planning, 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 274)
- Exploratory Project for Economic Alternatives, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 275)
- Exploratory Project for Economic Alternatives, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 276)
- Citizens Involvement Network, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 277)
- Minneapolis, MN, Third Sector Speech, 1977 June 30 (Box 30, Folder 278)
- Abortion Research, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 279)
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd Memorial Booklet, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 280)
- Bicentennial Era Testimony Drafts, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 281)
- Bicentennial Era Testimony, 1976 April 9 (Box 30, Folder 282)
- Citizens Involvement Network Projects, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 283)
- Future of Predominantly Black Colleges, 1969-1970 (Box 31, Folder 284)
- Reading File, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 285)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 286)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 287)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 288)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 289)
- Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1974-1977 (Box 31, Folder 290)
- Japan and Korea Trip, 1976 January (Box 31, Folder 291)
- Memorial Articles, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 292)
- Draft of Harr Book, circa 1978 (Box 32, Folder 293)
- Bicentennial Article, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 294)
- Bicentennial Legislation, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 295)
- Letters Concluding Bicentennial Work, 1976 July 12 (Box 32, Folder 296)
- Draft of Bicentennial Testimony, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 297)
- Bicentennial Planning, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 298)
- Bicentennial Task Force Meeting, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 299)
- Various State and Organization Bicentennial Plans, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 300)
- Third Sector Book Material, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 301)
- Third Sector Book Material, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 302)
- Exploratory Project for Economic Alternatives, 1976 March (Box 33, Folder 303)
- Educational Policy Center Inc., 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 304)
- Educational Policy Center Inc., 1972-1974 (Box 33, Folder 305)
- Urban Housing Information, 1969; 1973 (Box 33, Folder 306)
- Foundation for Cooperative Housing, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 307)
- Robert Swann Material on New Communities Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 308)
- Population Speech, Bucharest, 1974 July (Box 34, Folder 309)
- Population Speech Early Drafts, 1974 June (Box 34, Folder 310)
- Population Manifesto Drafts, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 311)
- Population Manifesto Drafts, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 312)
- Population Meeting, 1974 July 22 (Box 34, Folder 313)
- Population Statement Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 314)
- Abortion Background Material, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 315)
- Abortion Background Material, 1960s (Box 34, Folder 316)
- Association for the Study of Abortion, 1966-1969 (Box 35, Folder 317)
- Abortion Articles, 1967-1971 (Box 35, Folder 318)
- Population Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 35, Folder 319)
- Population Background Material, 1959-1964 (Box 35, Folder 320)
- Commission on Population Growth, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 321)